Finding Aid for the Ernst Toch Papers PASC-M.0001
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Toch's Library: Scores, Series 10.
  - Published Works, Subseries 2.
    - Fragment of piano reduction of Brahm's Symphony No. 2. 1 page of a reduction by Toch included. Berlin: N. Simrock, number 8172., pp. 29-43. (Box 179, Folder 1)
    - Fragment of 2 piano fugues. C.F. Peters number 6734., 4 p. (Box 179, Folder 2)
    - Gershwin, George. Porgy and Bess. New York: Gershwin Publishing Corporation, 1935., 559 p. (Box 179, Folder 3)
      Original unabridged version. Inscribed by Gershwin to Toch: "For Ernst - with keen appreciation of his music and with warm friendliness. George Gershwin. Apr. 1, 1936."
    - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix. Saemmtliche Kammermusik. Leipzig: Ernst Eulenburg, n.d. (Box 179, Folder 4)
    - Schubert, Franz. Kammermusik. Leipzig: Ernst Eulenberg, n.d. (Box 179, Folder 5)
- Interviews, Series 11.
  - Robert and Clair Trotter talk with Ren Weschler, 1972 August 1; open reel audio tape (Box 6, Folder 218)
  - Weschler - Lopatnikoff, 1972; open reel audio tape (Box 6, Folder 260)
  - Weschler - Stopler, 1972; open reel audio tape (Box 6, Folder 261)
  - They Remember Ernst Toch, 1967 December 23 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Final interview with Mrs. Toch conducted by William Malloch.
  - Mrs. Toch Speaks, open reel audio tape (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Interview conducted by William Malloch.
  - Ernst Toch, 1962 December; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 150)
    Interview conducted by Dr. Robert Frotter.
  - Converstaions with Mrs. Toch #1, 1967 June-July; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 151)
    Contents include: general histroy of Toch, cities of residence, etc. Background of Op. 1-28.
  - Conversations with Mrs. Toch #2, 1967 July; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 152)
    Discusses Op. 29-43, 44-52.
  - Conversations with Mrs. Toch #3, 1967 July; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 153)
    Contents include discussions of: Op. 53-65, 66-80.
  - Conversations with Mrs. Toch, 1967 July; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 154)
    Interview contents:, Op. 81-98, unnumbered compositions.
  - Converstaions with Mrs. Toch #1, 1967; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 155)
    Contents include: general history of Toch, cities of residence, etc. Background of Op. 1-28. (Side 1)
    Copy.
  - Converstaions with Mrs. Toch #1, 1967; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 156)
    Contents include: general history of Toch, cities of residence, etc. Background of Op. 1-28. (Side 2)
  - Conversations with Mrs. Toch #2, 1967; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 157)
    Discusses Op. 29-43, 44-52. (Side 1)
  - Conversations with Mrs. Toch #2, 1967; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 158)
    Discusses Op. 29-43, 44-52. (Side 2)
  - Conversations with Mrs. Toch #3, 1967; open reel audio tape, 1 in. (Box 209, Folder 159)
    Conversation includes discussion of: Op. 53-65, 66-80. (Side 1)
  - Conversations with Mrs. Toch #3, 1967; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 160)
    Conversation contents include: Op. 53-65, 66-80.
  - William Malloch with Mrs. Ernst Toch, 1967 December; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 161)
  - Malloch with Lili Toch, 1967; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 162)
    With interpolations of old Toch statements.
  - Mrs. Toch Speaks, Part 1, open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 163)
    An interview by William Malloch from KPFK (recorded off the air).
  - Mrs. Toch Speaks, Part 2, open reel audio tape, 1 in. (Box 209, Folder 164)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Herbert Zipper, 1972 December; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 165)
    Other conversation participants: Ren, Robert, Franzi Weschler.
  - Dr. Hugo Strelitzer on Ernst Toch, 1973 September; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 166)
    Ren Weschler.
  - Mel Powell, Ren Weschler, 1973 January; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 167)
    Date of interview is questionable.
  - Judith Heller, Lawrence Weschler, 1972 October; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 168)
  - Mrs. Liesel Lehmann, Ren Weschler, Franz Weschler, 1972 September; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 169)
  - John Scott Trotter, Ren Weschler, Diane Jezak, 1972 July; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 170)
  - Weschler - Temianka on Toch, 1972 November; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 171)
  - Peter Jona Korn - Ren Weschler on Ernst Toch, 1972 December; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 172)
  - Elsa Roman, 1972 July; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 173)
    Elsa Roman is Toch's sister. Other speakers include: Diane Jezik, Franzi Weschler, Rennie Weschler.
  - Aurelia de la Vega. Diane Jecek - Ren Weschler, 1972 July; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 174)
  - Matt Doran, 1972 July; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 175)
    Speakers include: Ren Weschler, Diane Jecek.
  - Lawrence Weschler on Ernst Toch, open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 176)
  - Sam Jaffe on Toch, open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 177)
  - Dr. Pauline Alderman, 1973; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 178)
    Interview conducted by Dr. Matt Doran.
    Part of the Ernst Toch oral history project.
  - "They Remember Ernst Toch", 1967 December; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 179)
    (William Malloch) Recorded off the air from KPFK. Tape 1.
  - "They Remember Ernst Toch", 1967 December; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 180)
    Speaker: William Malloch. Recorded off the air from KPFK. Tape 2.
  - William Malloch, open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 181)
    Incomplete interview.
  - Ernst Toch, 1962 November 8; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 182)
    Interviewed by Dr. Robert Trotter.
- Realia and Miscellanous, Series 12.
  Realia and Miscellanous material. Boxes 180-194.
  - Miscellaneous momentos belonging to Ernst and Lilly. Some of Ernst's dreams and drawings. (Box 180)
  - Der Faecher. Program and audio recordings from the 1994 performance. (Box 183, Folder 1)
  - Scheherazade [The Last Tale, Op. 88]. Items related to the premiere including audio/visual recordings, photographs, programs, correspondence., 1995 (Box 183, Folder 2)
  - Uncatalogued newspaper clippings. (Box 184)
  - Miscellany: Villa Majestic Guest Book, letter folio, cover to published Op. 9, cover to sketch holder. (Box 185)
  - miscellaneous notebooks/journals (Box 186)
  - envelopes (Box 187)
    primarily from correspondence with John Bass. Save for autographs?
  - Artwork: Drawings and Paintings of Ernst and Lilly. (Box 188)
  - Archive-related materials (Box 189)
    Includes items from the Toch Festival.
  - Passport folio and datebooks 1948-1963 (Box 190)
  - Address books belonging to Tochs (Box 191)
  - Items from Toch Festival: Captions and other material. (Box 192)
  - Unprocessed material, mostly correspondence (Box 194)
  - Unprocessed material, mostly correspondence (Box 194b)
  - Unprocessed material, mostly correspondence (Box 195)
    Includes correspondence of the UCLA Ernst Toch Fund.
  - Unprocessed material, mostly correspondence (Box 214)
  - Unprocessed material, mostly correspondence (Box 215)
  - Papers of Ella Zwack (Lilly's Mother). (Box 216)
    Includes correspondence and documentary of Ella Zwack's escape from occupied France.
  - Papers of Ella Zwack (Lilly's Mother). (Box 217)
    Includes correspondence.
  - Papers of Ella Zwack (Lilly's Mother). (Box 218)
  - Uncatalogued correspondence - Lilly Toch (Box 219)
  - Uncatalogued correspondence - Lilly Toch (Box 220)
  - Uncatalogued correspondence - Lilly Toch (Box 222)
  - Papers of Ella Zwack (Lilly's Mother). (Box 224)
  - Unprocessed material, mostly correspondence
    Includes UCLA Ernst Toch Fund mailing lists.
- Lawrence Weschler Collection, Series 13.
  Material donated to the Archive by Toch's grandson, Lawrence Weschler. Box 197.
  - Collected criticism from Pittsburgh Press (Box 197, Folder 1)
  - Alfred Leonard Correspondence (may duplicate regular correspondence) (Box 197, Folder 2)
  - Toch-Coolidge Correspondence (Box 197, Folder 3)
  - Mills-Toch Correspondence (Box 197, Folder 4)
  - AMP-Toch Correspondence (Box 197, Folder 5)
  - Cohn correspondence (Box 197, Folder 6)
  - Hilda and Melville Rollman Branch (Toch family friends) (Box 197, Folder 7)
  - Weschler Family Estate (Box 197, Folder 8)
  - Handwritten anniversary note to Lilly, 1964. (Box 197, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 197, Folder 10)
  - Steven Honigberg Performs Toch Cello Sonata (Box 197, Folder 11)
  - Jacob Avshalomov (student of Toch) (Box 197, Folder 12)
  - Lester Koenig Interview (Box 197, Folder 13)
  - Toch miscellany from Ren (Lawrence Weschler), June 1998. (Box 197, Folder 14)
  - Siegfried Toch (Box 197, Folder 15)
  - Ernst Toch: A Chronology (Box 197, Folder 16)
  - Lawrence Weschler Correspondence (Box 197, Folder 17)
  - Articles by Lawrence Weschler (Box 197, Folder 18)
  - Vermeer in Bosnia: a reader, 2004; 412 pages (Box 197, Folder 19)
    Includes the article "My Grandfather's Last Tale", reprinted from the Atlantic Monthly, December 1996.
- Toni Weschler Collection, Series 14.
  Material donated to the Archive by Toch's grandaughter, Toni Weschler. Box 198-202.
  - Letters 1960-1964. (Box 198, Folder 1)
  - Poems (Box 198, Folder 2)
  - Deutscher Komponisten-Verband Correspondence (Box 198, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1988 (Box 198, Folder 4)
  - "European Radio Stations I contacted" (Box 198, Folder 5)
  - Radio Stations - Chamber Groups (Box 198, Folder 6)
  - Cantata of the Bitter Herbs Correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 198, Folder 7)
  - Toch, Ernst. "Some Thoughts Out of Season." Notes, The Quarterly Journal of the Performing Arts Special Collections Association, v. 22, no. 3, March 1966, p. 1003. (Box 199, Folder 1)
  - Photo: Franzi Weschler, Toni Weschler, Lawrence Weschler (Box 199, Folder 2)
  - Photo: Lilly Toch (Box 199, Folder 3)
  - Photo: Ernst Toch at the piano (duplicate) (Box 199, Folder 4)
  - Lilly Toch Memorial April 23, 1972 (Box 199, Folder 5)
  - Transcription of interview between Ernst Toch and Dr. Robert Trotter, November 8, 1962; 21 pages typescript, xerox (Box 199, Folder 6-7)
    Bill Malloch's Documentation
  - Orchestration of a composers life, v. 2 (Box 199, Folder 8)
    Orchestration of a composers life, v. 2, Lilly Toch. pages 874-883, 895-896, 913-914, 916-919. xerox copies, annotated in margins Bill Malloch's Documentation
  - Ernst Toch discography (Box 199, Folder 9)
    typescript xerox, 6 pages Bill Malloch's Documentation
  - Weschler, Franzi Toch September 18, 1987 (Box 199, Folder 10)
    letter to Mr. Zeidberg from Franzi Toch Wechsler, typescript xerox, 2 pages, annotated Bill Malloch's Documentation
  - Interview with William Malloch and Ren Weschler. (Box 199, Folder 11)
    One compact audio cassette and one 5.25 inch floppy disk.
  - First and final report of executrix, .. (Box 199, Folder 12)
    "First and final report of executrix, waiver of accounting, petition for fees and comissions and for final distribution", xerox, 8 pages Alice Toch estate, final papers
  - Receipt for statutory commissions (Box 199, Folder 13)
    xerox Alice Toch estate, final papers
  - Certificate of death Apr 19, 1972 (Box 199, Folder 14)
    3 xerox copies Alice Toch estate, final papers
  - Letters Testamentary Jun 23, 1972 (Box 199, Folder 15)
    xerox copy Alice Toch estate, final papers
  - Alice Toch Estate, assets & disbursements (Box 199, Folder 16)
    handwritten Alice Toch estate, final papers
  - State of California inheritance tax declaration, form IT-22 (Box 199, Folder 17)
    4 pages, xerox Alice Toch estate, final papers
  - United States estate tax return, form 706 (Box 199, Folder 18)
    16 pages, xerox copy Alice Toch estate, final papers
  - Individual income tax return, form 1040 (Box 199, Folder 19)
    8 pages, copy Alice Toch estate, final papers
  - Fiduciary California income tax, form 541 (Box 199, Folder 20)
    5 pages, copy Alice Toch estate, final papers
  - Ernst Toch estate tax liability - federal March 31, 1967 (Box 199, Folder 21)
    page typescript with attached notes (5 pieces) + 2 copies Alice Toch estate, final papers
  - Estate tax closing letter Jul 27, 1973 (Box 199, Folder 22)
    Alice Toch estate, final papers
  - Estate tax closing letter, May 5 1967 (Box 199, Folder 23)
  - Affidavit or declaration for final discharge and order Sept. 8 1975 (Box 199, Folder 24)
  - Shearer, Jacob. Letter to Franzi Wechsler, 25 April 1972 (Box 199, Folder 25)
    typescript
  - Shearer, Jacob. Letter to Franzi Wechsler, 23 May, 1972 (Box 199, Folder 26)
  - Shearer, Jacob. Letter to Franzi Wechsler, 5 June 1972 (Box 199, Folder 27)
  - Shearer, Jacob. Letter to Franzi Wechsler, 16 June 1972 (Box 199, Folder 28)
  - Shearer, Jacob. Letter to Franzi Wechsler, 24 August 1972 (Box 199, Folder 29)
  - Shearer, Jacob. Letter to Franzi Wechsler, 1 September 1972 (Box 199, Folder 30)
  - Shearer, Jacob. Letter to Franzi Wechsler, 14 March 1973 (Box 199, Folder 31)
  - Shearer, Jacob. Letter to Franzi Wechsler, 20 July 1973 (Box 199, Folder 32)
  - Shearer, Jacob, Letter to Franzi Wechsler, December 21, 1973 (Box 199, Folder 33)
  - Shearer, Jacob. Letter to Franzi Wechsler, April 10, 1974 (Box 199, Folder 34)
  - Shearer, Jacob. Letter to Franzi Wechsler, April 16, 1974 (Box 199, Folder 35)
  - Shearer, Jacob. Letter to Franzi Wechsler, June 21, 1974 (Box 199, Folder 36)
  - Architectural forum magazine of building, the May 1946, Vol 84, No 5 (Box 199, Folder 37)
    (see page 85) xerox duplicate of p. 85, layout of Toch's home
  - Photo: Toch and Feri Roth (duplicate) (Box 200, Folder 1)
  - Toni Stolper Notes on "Talks on Toch" lecture. (Box 200, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper article: "Banned in Berlin" from Forward, 4 June 1993. (Box 200, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper article: "Mauceri Resurrects Forgotten Sounds of Germany" from LA Times, 24 July 1993. (Box 200, Folder 4)
  - Lawrence Weschler Correspondence regarding Toch Festival. (Box 200, Folder 5)
  - Michael Mann, ed. Das Thomas Mann-Buch: Eine innere Biographie in Selbstzeugnissen. Frankfurt am Main: Fischer Buecherei, 1965. (Box 201, Folder 1)
  - Young, Betty Lou. Pacific Palisades: Where the Mountains Meet the Sea. Pacific Palisades, CA: Pacific Palisades Historical Society Press, 1983. (Box 201, Folder 2)
    Inscribed to Lawrence Weschler by the author.
  - Riegl, Ingeborg and Michael Caroli. Mannheim: ehemals, gestern und heute. Mannheim: Edition Quadrat, 1987. (Box 201, Folder 3)
  - Heinz, Kurt. Liebes Altes Mannheim. Mannheim: Verlag Dr. Haas KG, 1966. (Box 201, Folder 4)
  - Lindemann, Anna-Maria. Mannheim im Kaiserreich. Mannheim: Edition Quadrat, 1988. (Box 201, Folder 5)
  - Miscellany (Box 202, Folder 1)
- Recent Acquisitions, Series 15.
  Recently donated items related to the carreer of Toch.
  - Mrs. Toch Speaks, open reel audio tape (Box 8, Folder 5)
    An interview by William Malloch.
  - Letters Related to Ingolf Dahl/ Notes for Cello and Piano Concertos (Box 205, Folder 1)
    Donated by Dr. Anthony Linick
  - "Remembering Toch" Program and clippings from Ernst Toch Society concert, November 30, 2000 (Box 205, Folder 2)
  - Erwin, Charlotte E. "Ernst Toch in the United States." Modern Austrian Literature, Vol. 20, Nos. 3-4, 1987. (Box 205, Folder 3)
  - Lawrence Weschler. Article from UC paper., February 1973 (Box 205, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous photocopies from Heiko Schneider, including essay about Kaufmann emigre' painting. (Box 205, Folder 5)
  - Program from Bard Music Festival, August 1992 (Box 205, Folder 6)
  - Brochures from Ernst Toch Symposium, November 2000 (Box 205, Folder 7)
  - Oesterreichische Musik Zeitschrift, Oct/Nov 1990 (Box 205, Folder 7)
  - Anectode from Kate T. Steinmetz regarding Lilly Toch (Box 205, Folder 8)